

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT · AUTONOMOUS SYSTEMS GROUP · THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN

💌 fdjeumou@utexas.edu | 🏕 franckdjeumou.github.io | 🖸 wuwushrek | 🛅 franck-djeumou-626613202 | 📓 Franck Djeumou

## Research Interests

My research lies broadly at the intersection of learning with prior knowledge, control theory, formal methods, and optimization. Specifically, I investigate how prior knowledge (e.g., laws of Physics, properties empirically validated through engineering experiments) can be incorporated into learning agents to improve the data efficiency and generalization, and how such side information can be used for the formal verification of the agents, particularly in the context of safety-critical applications such as aircraft control and robotics.

## Education \_\_

#### The University of Texas at Austin

Austin, USA

September 2018 - May 2023 (Expected)

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

• Ph.D. Advisor: Ufuk Topcu

• Cumulative GPA Over 30 Credits (Ph.D. Major Course Requirements): 3.96

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE AND MASTER OF SCIENCE IN AEROSPACE ENGINEERING

#### ISAE-SUPAERO (Institut Supérieur de l'Aéronautique et de l'Espace)

Toulouse, France

September 2014 - June 2018

Advised by Prof. Jerome Hugues

- Cumulative GPA: 3.8 | Top 4% of the class
- Thesis on "Safety Guarantees for Drones through Set-Based Formal Verification Methods"

### École Polytechnique

Palaiseau France

September 2016 - September 2017

MASTER DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (COMASIC)

- Advised by Prof. Eric Goubault and Prof. Sylvie Putot
- Cumulative GPA: 3.7 | Graduated with Honours
- Thesis on "Human-Embedded Autonomous Flight Under Formal Task Specifications"
- This master degree was obtained as a collaboration between ISAE-SUPAERO and École Polytechnique

Lycée Fénelon Paris, France

CLASS PREPARATORY (EQUIVALENT TO JUNIOR UNDERGRADUATE LEVEL) IN MATHEMATICS, PHYSICS, AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

September 2011 - June 2014

· 6th out of 42 students

# **Experience**

## Autonomous Systems Group

Austin, USA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

September 2018 - Present

- Published 9 conference papers (with 5 papers currently under review) and 6 journal papers (with 3 papers currently under review)
- Collaborated with researchers from various academic institutions, national research laboratories and companies, and presented research outcomes at more than 5 invited talks.

#### Cosynus Team at Laboratory LIX of École Polytechnique

Palaiseau, France

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISORS: ERIC GOUBAULT AND SYLVIE PUTOT

March 2018 - August 2018

- Designed and Built the quadrotor testbed for the research team based on Crazyflie drones
- Implemented a hardware and software in the loop, Gazebo-based swarm simulator for the Crazyflie drones
- The code for the simulator is publicly available at www.shrek/sim\_cf and has over 20 stars and 20 forks on GitHub.
- · Investigated safety of dynamical systems through Taylor-based methods and abstract interpretation
- Investigated on-the-fly, lightweight and real-time verification (reach and safety properties) algorithms to be embedded on Crazyflie drones

### **Autonomous Systems Group (UT Austin)**

Austin, USA

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

March 2017 - August 2017

- Designed and built quadrotors based on the Snapdragon Platform and PX4 as the autopilot. Implemented a fast trajectory generator for quadrotors based on the minimum snap approach via a new problem modeling
- Investigated human interface with virtual reality and autonomous flight of a quadrotor via eye-tracking (youtube.com/watch?v=AfosHcWR9M)
- Investigated the problem of tracking moving targets using POMDPs (Partially Observable Markov Decision Process) and human inputs
- Designed model checking and planning algorithms for UAVs autonomous missions with specifications expressed in temporal logic

### **Liebherr Aerospace and Transportation**

Toulouse, France

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

June 2015 - August 2015

- · Implementation in R of supervised learning algorithms to automatically classify aircraft's equipments from a reliability point of view
- Designed and implemented an application in Java that interacts with Liebherr's database to provide classification results to an expert



French (native), English (fluent), Japanese (beginner) Languages

Python, C++, C, Java, C#, R, Matlab, HTML5/CSS3 | My GitHub stats estimate more than 100k lines of code **Programming** 

**Tools & Technologies** ROS, Jax, TensorFlow, Unity, Gazebo, PX4 Autopilot, Crazyflie, MuJoCo, RTOS, CVXPY, Gurobi, Mosek, Arduino

> Sports Tennis, Soccer, Running, Biking, Skiing

## **Publications**

\* indicates equal contribution

## PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE ARTICLES [9]

Taylor-Lagrange Neural Ordinary Differential Equations: Toward Fast Training and Evaluation of Neural ODEs

Franck Djeumou\*, Cyrus Neary\*, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2022

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.05715

Neural Networks with Physics-Informed Architectures and Constraints for Dynamical Systems Modeling

Franck Djeumou\*, Cyrus Neary\*, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC) 2022

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06407

Learning to Reach, Swim, Walk and Fly in One Trial: Data-Driven Control with Scarce Data and Side Information

Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC) 2022

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.10533

2021

Task-Guided Inverse Reinforcement Learning Under Partial Information

Franck Djeumou, Murat Cubuktepe, Craig Lennon, Ufuk Topcu

**Under Review** at International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS) 2022

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.14073

2022

2021

Blending Controllers via Multi-Objective Bandits

Parham Gohari\*, Franck Djeumou\*, Abraham P Vinod, Ufuk Topcu

Under review at the 2022 American Control Conference (ACC) as an invited paper

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2007.15755

2021

Learning-Based, Safety-Constrained Control from Scarce Data via Reciprocal Barriers

Christos K Verginis, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Conference on Decision and Control

URL: https://cverginis.github.io/publications/conferences/CDC21\_safety.pdf

On-the-fly, Data-driven Reachability Analysis and Control of Unknown Systems: An F-16 Aircraft Case Study (Best Demo/Poster Award)

Franck Djeumou, Aditya Zutshi, Ufuk Topcu International Conference on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control (HSCC 2021)

URL: https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3447928.3457355

On-The-Fly Control of Unknown Smooth Systems from Limited Data

Franck Djeumou, Abraham P. Vinod, Éric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

2021 American Control Conference (ACC)

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9483367

Probabilistic Swarm Guidance Subject to Graph Temporal Logic Specifications

Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Ufuk Topcu

Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)

 $\verb|URL: http://www.roboticsproceedings.org/rss16/p058.pdf|\\$ 

### JOURNAL ARTICLES [6]

Task-Guided IRL on POMDPs at Scale with Information Asymmetry

Franck Djeumou, Christian Ellis, Murat Cubuktepe, Craig Lennon, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at the special issue VSI:Risk-Aware Autonomy for consideration at the journal of Artificial Intelligence (2022). Elsevier

Probabilistic Control of Heterogeneous Swarms Subject to Graph Temporal Logic Specifications: A Decentralized and Scalable Approach

Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Murat Cubuktepe, Ufuk Topcu

Conditionally accepted at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (IEE TAC) (2021). IEEE URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.15729

2021

Safety-Constrained Learning and Control using Scarce Data and Reciprocal Barriers

Christos K Verginis, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021). IEEE

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06526

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2011.05524

On-The-Fly Control of Unknown Systems: From Side Information to Performance Guarantees through Reachability

Franck Djeumou, Abraham P Vinod, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021). IEEE

Policy Synthesis for Switched Linear Systems with Markov Decision Process Switching

Bo Wu, Murat Cubuktepe, Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Ufuk Topcu

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.12733

Online Synthesis for Runtime Enforcement of Safety in Multi-Agent Systems

Dhananjay Raju, Sudarshanan Bharadwaj, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu IEEE Transactions on Control of Network Systems (2021). IEEE

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9362272 2021

## Honors & Awards

2021	<b>Winner</b> , Best Demo/Poster Award at Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Hybrid Systems:	Nashville, USA
	Computation and Control (HSCC 2021)	
2017	Scholarship, Foundation of Ecole Polytechnique	Palaiseau, France
2017	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2016	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2015	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2014	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France

## Professional Services

#### WORKSHOPS ORGANIZED

#### Workshop on Safe and Reliable Robot Autonomy under Uncertainty

Philadelphia, USA

May 2022

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA) Co-organizer

### REVIEWER

I was a reviewer at the following journals and conferences.

- IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021)
- International Conference on Robotics and Automation (2021)
- American Control Conference (2020, 2021)
- IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (2021)
- IFAC symposium system identification (2021)

## Invited Talks\_\_\_\_

2021	Incorporating Physics-Based Knowledge into Neural Network Dynamics Models, Galois Inc: Final Briefing for the Assured Autonomy Project	Austin, USA
2021	Learning How to Reach, Swim, Walk and Fly in One Trial,	Austin, USA
	Professor Karen E. Willcox's Research Group	
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb,	Austin, USA
	Lockheed Martin	
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb,	Austin, USA
	Texas Robotics Symposium	
2021	Data-Driven, On-The-Fly Reachability and Control of Unknown Systems,	
	Mini-Symposium on "Leaning for Dynamical Systems and Control" at the SIAM Conference on Applications of	Portland, USA
	Dynamical Systems	
2020	Learning On-the-Fly with a Case Study in Hypersonic Flight,	Austin, USA
	Sandia National Laboratories: Autonomy for Hypersonics Virtual Field Day	

# References \_\_\_\_

- · Prof. Ufuk Topcu, Assistant Professor (Controls, Autonomy and Robotics), The University of Texas at Austin, USA
- Prof. Eric Goubault, Professor (Computer Science), École Polytechnique, France
- Prof. Sylvie Putot, Professor (Computer Science), École Polytechnique, France